<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<mods:mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/mods-3-7.xsd">
    <mods:titleInfo>
        <mods:title>BLM Colorado Coal Lease Cases (Authorized and Pending) Polygons</mods:title>
    </mods:titleInfo>
    <mods:name authority="lcnaf" valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n80125846">
        <mods:namePart>U.S. Department of the Interior, Bureau of Land Management (BLM)</mods:namePart>
        <mods:role>
            <mods:roleTerm type="text">publisher</mods:roleTerm>
        </mods:role>
    </mods:name>
    <mods:name authority="lcnaf" valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n80125846">
        <mods:namePart>U.S. Department of the Interior, Bureau of Land Management (BLM)</mods:namePart>
        <mods:role>
            <mods:roleTerm type="text">creator</mods:roleTerm>
        </mods:role>
    </mods:name>
    <mods:typeOfResource>cartographic</mods:typeOfResource>
    <mods:typeOfResource>software, multimedia</mods:typeOfResource>
    <mods:accessCondition />
    <mods:originInfo>
        <mods:dateCreated encoding="w3cdtf" />
        <mods:dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">20200911</mods:dateIssued>
        <mods:place>
            <mods:placeTerm>Colorado</mods:placeTerm>
        </mods:place>
        <mods:publisher>U.S. Department of the Interior, Bureau of Land Management (BLM)</mods:publisher>
    </mods:originInfo>
    <mods:language>
        <mods:languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</mods:languageTerm>
    </mods:language>
    <mods:subject authority="fast" valueURI="http://id.worldcat.org/fast/fst01022541">
        <mods:topic>Mines and mineral resources</mods:topic>
    </mods:subject>
    <mods:subject authority="fast" valueURI="http://id.worldcat.org/fast/fst00865278">
        <mods:topic>Coal leases</mods:topic>
    </mods:subject>
    <mods:subject authority="fast" valueURI="http://id.worldcat.org/fast/fst01074275">
        <mods:topic>Energy</mods:topic>
    </mods:subject>
    <mods:subject authority="fast" valueURI="http://id.worldcat.org/fast/1210251">
        <mods:geographic>Colorado</mods:geographic>
    </mods:subject>
    <mods:subject>
        <mods:cartographics>
            <mods:coordinates>W108.847584,W37.103573,N104.897552,N40.490666</mods:coordinates>
        </mods:cartographics>
    </mods:subject>
    <mods:physicalDescription>
        <mods:digitalOrigin>born digital</mods:digitalOrigin>
        <mods:form authority="LCGFT" authorityURI="https://id.loc.gov/authorities/genreForms/gf2011026297">Geospatial data</mods:form>
        <mods:note> Version 6.2 (Build 9200) ; Esri ArcGIS 10.5.1.7333</mods:note>
        <mods:internetMediaType>application/octet-stream</mods:internetMediaType>
    </mods:physicalDescription>
    <mods:identifier type="local">BLM_CO_COAL_LEASES_SHP.xml</mods:identifier>
    <mods:identifier type="ark">https://ark.colorado.edu/ark:/47540/gs4t9863f7qp</mods:identifier>
    <mods:abstract>Shapefile Format –The BLM Colorado State Office periodically generates the GIS dataset for authorized and pending coal lease cases. Lease records are selected from BLM’s LR2000 database for the following case types:340001 –Coal lease341001 –Coal exploration license342001 –Regional coal lease - competitive342504 –Regional competitive emergency/bypass342505 –Non-regional competitive coal lease - LBA342506 –Coal lease - hardship343001 –Coal lease preference right. A Python script then uses the legal land descriptions contained in the extracted LR2000 records to generate a shapefile. BLM’s Geographic Coordinate Database (GCDB) is used as a geographic reference to create the polygon features in the lease GIS dataset. The GIS dataset is projected to NAD83/UTM13N and any geometry errors introduced during processing are repaired.Display generalized authorized and pending coal lease cases created from LR2000 records.Description of the Error Spreadsheet: BLM uses a Python script to automatically generate polygon shapefiles from legal land descriptions contained in LR2000 records. The script does this by looking for a polygon in BLM's GCDB database to match the LR2000 land description and then cloning or subdividing the polygon in the new shapefile. The error spreadsheet that accompanies the downloadable data contains LR2000 records which the script wasn't able to match to GCDB polygons. This typically occurs for one of two reasons. Either the LR2000 record didn't contain a valid legal land description, or the script wasn't able to find a unique polygon in the reference GCDB database to match the legal land description provided in LR2000.A published revision of the Department Manuals Part 305: Departmental Science Effects, Chapter 3: Integrity of Scientific and Scholarly Activities (305 DM 3), effective December 16, 2014, is available online at http://elips.doi.gov/ELIPS/DocView.aspx?id=4056. Scholarly information considered in Departmental decision making must be robust, of the highest quality, and the result of as rigorous scientific and scholarly processes as can be achieved. Most importantly, it must be trustworthy. This policy helps us to achieve that standard (http://www.doi.gov/scientificintegrity/index.cfm)BLM Colorado - Coal Lease Cases (Authorized and Pending)</mods:abstract>
    <mods:note>These data are provided by Bureau of Land Management (BLM) “as is” and might contain errors or omissions. The User assumes the entire risk associated with its use of these data and bears all responsibility in determining whether these data are fit for the User’s intended use. The information contained in these data is dynamic and may change over time. The data are not better than the sources from which they were derived, and both scale and accuracy may vary across the data set. These data might not have the accuracy, resolution, completeness, timeliness, or other characteristics appropriate for applications that potential users of the data may contemplate. The User is encouraged to carefully consider the content of the metadata file associated with these data. These data are neither legal documents nor land surveys, and must not be used as such. Official records may be referenced at most BLM offices. Please report any errors in the data to the BLM office from which it was obtained.</mods:note>
    <mods:accessCondition ns2:href="https://rightsstatements.org/page/NoC-US/1.0/?language=en">The
        organization that has made the Item available believes that the Item is in the Public Domain
        under the laws of the United States, but a determination was not made as to its copyright
        status under the copyright laws of other countries. The Item may not be in the Public Domain
        under the laws of other countries. Please refer to the organization that has made the Item
        available for more information.</mods:accessCondition>
    
    <mods:relatedItem type="original">
        <mods:titleInfo>
            <mods:title>BLM Colorado Coal Lease Cases (Authorized and Pending) Polygons</mods:title>
        </mods:titleInfo>
        <mods:location>
            <mods:url access="object in context">https://navigator.blm.gov</mods:url>
        </mods:location>
    </mods:relatedItem>
    <mods:recordInfo>
        <mods:recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-11-04</mods:recordCreationDate>
        <mods:recordOrigin>Record created using source metadata and additional metadata provided by the University of Colorado Boulder Libraries.</mods:recordOrigin>
        <mods:recordContentSource>University of Colorado Boulder Libraries</mods:recordContentSource>
    </mods:recordInfo>
</mods:mods>