<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<mods:mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/mods-3-7.xsd">
    <mods:titleInfo>
        <mods:title>BLM Colorado Solid Non-Energy Leasable Minerals</mods:title>
    </mods:titleInfo>
    <mods:name authority="lcnaf" valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n80125846">
        <mods:namePart>U.S. Department of the Interior, Bureau of Land Management (BLM)</mods:namePart>
        <mods:role>
            <mods:roleTerm type="text">publisher</mods:roleTerm>
        </mods:role>
    </mods:name>
    <mods:name authority="lcnaf" valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n80125846">
        <mods:namePart>U.S. Department of the Interior, Bureau of Land Management (BLM)</mods:namePart>
        <mods:role>
            <mods:roleTerm type="text">creator</mods:roleTerm>
        </mods:role>
    </mods:name>
    <mods:typeOfResource>cartographic</mods:typeOfResource>
    <mods:typeOfResource>software, multimedia</mods:typeOfResource>
    <mods:accessCondition />
    <mods:originInfo>
        <mods:dateCreated encoding="w3cdtf" />
        <mods:dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">20200418</mods:dateIssued>
        <mods:place>
            <mods:placeTerm>Colorado</mods:placeTerm>
        </mods:place>
        <mods:publisher>U.S. Department of the Interior, Bureau of Land Management (BLM)</mods:publisher>
    </mods:originInfo>
    <mods:language>
        <mods:languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</mods:languageTerm>
    </mods:language>
    <mods:subject authority="fast" valueURI="http://id.worldcat.org/fast/fst01749490">
        <mods:topic>Solid minerals</mods:topic>
    </mods:subject>
    <mods:subject authority="fast" valueURI="http://id.worldcat.org/fast/fst01022445">
        <mods:topic>Minerals</mods:topic>
    </mods:subject>
    <mods:subject authority="fast" valueURI="http://id.worldcat.org/fast/fst00837076">
        <mods:topic>Boundaries</mods:topic>
    </mods:subject>
    <mods:subject authority="fast" valueURI="http://id.worldcat.org/fast/fst00940627">
        <mods:topic>Geology</mods:topic>
    </mods:subject>
    <mods:subject authority="fast" valueURI="http://id.worldcat.org/fast/1210251">
        <mods:geographic>Colorado</mods:geographic>
    </mods:subject>
    <mods:subject>
        <mods:cartographics>
            <mods:coordinates>W109.188567,W37.816022,N104.008181,N40.790718</mods:coordinates>
        </mods:cartographics>
    </mods:subject>
    <mods:physicalDescription>
        <mods:digitalOrigin>born digital</mods:digitalOrigin>
        <mods:form authority="LCGFT" authorityURI="https://id.loc.gov/authorities/genreForms/gf2011026297">Geospatial data</mods:form>
        <mods:note>Microsoft Windows Server 2008 R2 Version 6.1 (Build 7601) Service Pack 1; Esri ArcGIS 10.4.1.5686</mods:note>
        <mods:internetMediaType>application/octet-stream</mods:internetMediaType>
    </mods:physicalDescription>
    <mods:identifier type="local">BLM_CO_SNEL_SHP.xml</mods:identifier>
    <mods:identifier type="ark">https://ark.colorado.edu/ark:/47540/6m7095552910</mods:identifier>
    <mods:abstract>The Solid Non-energy Leasable (SNEL) minerals data set was generated using records extracted from BLM’s LR2000 case record database. The record selection criteria specified authorized and pending prospecting permits, preference right leases, exploration leases, competitive leases, noncompetitive leases and use permits for the following commodities:(1) Phosphate (pho) (2) Sodium (sod) (3) Potassium (pot) (4) Sulfur (sul) (5) Gilsonite (gil) (6) Hardrock minerals (hdr) The three-character category codes shown above in parentheses can be used to easily select subsets of records based on the commodity. This data set has been projected to the UTM13N/NAD83 coordinate system.Shapefile Format -To illustrate Solid Non-Energy Leasable Minerals for the State of ColoradoError Records: There are typically some LR2000 records for which we are not able to generate corresponding polygons, but in this case all of the selected land descriptions were successfully converted to GIS features. See the associated Error report for any uncoverted features.SNEL Polygon</mods:abstract>
    <mods:note>These data are provided by Bureau of Land Management (BLM) “as is” and might contain errors or omissions.  The User assumes the entire risk associated with its use of these data and bears all responsibility in determining whether these data are fit for the User’s intended use.   

The information contained in these data is dynamic and may change over time.  The data are not better than the sources from which they were derived, and both scale and accuracy may vary across the data set.  These data might not have the accuracy, resolution, completeness, timeliness, or other characteristics appropriate for applications that potential users of the data may contemplate.  The User is encouraged to carefully consider the content of the metadata file associated with these data.  These data are neither legal documents nor land surveys, and must not be used as such.  Official records may be referenced at most BLM offices.  Please report any errors in the data to the BLM office from which it was obtained.  

The BLM should be cited as the data source in any products derived from these data.  Any Users wishing to modify the data should describe the types of modifications they have performed.  The User should not misrepresent the data, nor imply that changes made were approved or endorsed by BLM.  This data may be updated by the BLM without notification.</mods:note>
    <mods:accessCondition ns2:href="https://rightsstatements.org/page/NoC-US/1.0/?language=en">The
        organization that has made the Item available believes that the Item is in the Public Domain
        under the laws of the United States, but a determination was not made as to its copyright
        status under the copyright laws of other countries. The Item may not be in the Public Domain
        under the laws of other countries. Please refer to the organization that has made the Item
        available for more information.</mods:accessCondition>
   
    <mods:relatedItem type="original">
        <mods:titleInfo>
            <mods:title>BLM Colorado Solid Non-Energy Leasable Minerals</mods:title>
        </mods:titleInfo>
        <mods:location>
            <mods:url access="object in context">https://navigator.blm.gov</mods:url>
        </mods:location>
    </mods:relatedItem>
    <mods:recordInfo>
        <mods:recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2020-11-04</mods:recordCreationDate>
        <mods:recordOrigin>Record created using source metadata and additional metadata provided by the University of Colorado Boulder Libraries.</mods:recordOrigin>
        <mods:recordContentSource>University of Colorado Boulder Libraries</mods:recordContentSource>
    </mods:recordInfo>
</mods:mods>